This dataset was processed based on another raw dataset. Experiment set up and other detailed information of the orginal dataset can be found in Appendix 1 and Appendix 2 below.
This dataset was prepared by HYY on 01 Jun 2018.

********************************
**【Files within this dataset】 **
********************************
1. README.txt
2. CodeBook.txt - Indicate all the variables and summaries calculated, along with units, and any other relevant information.
3. Assignmentoutput.txt - This is the cleaned dataset which contains the summarize information for the original dataset
4. run_analysis.R - This is the R source code containing scripts which process the original dataset to the cleaned dataset output(3.Assignmentoutput.txt) 

*********************************************
**【Appendix 1: Original Experiment set up】 **
*********************************************
-Sample: Volunteers
-Sample size: 30
-Age range: 19-48
-Activities: 
    1 WALKING

    2 WALKING_UPSTAIRS

    3 WALKING_DOWNSTAIRS

    4 SITTING

    5 STANDING

    6 LAYING

-Data source: Sensor signals from a smartphone (Samsung Galaxy S II), which is wore by the volunteers while performing activities.
  i.3-axial linear acceleration(Denoted X/Y/Z) measured by embedded accelerometer at a constant rate of 50Hz
  ii. 3-axial angular velocity(Denoted X/Y/Z) measured by embedded gyroscope at a constant rate of 50Hz
-Labeling of activities:The experiments have been video-recorded to label the data manually.
-Organization of data:The obtained dataset has been randomly partitioned into two sets, where 70% of the volunteers was selected for generating the training data and 30% the test data. 
-Processing of data:
The sensor signals (accelerometer and gyroscope) were pre-processed by
  i.applying noise filters
  ii.sampled in fixed-width sliding windows of 2.56 sec and 50% overlap (128 readings/window)
  iii.The sensor acceleration signal, which has gravitational and body motion components, was separated using a Butterworth low-pass filter into body acceleration and gravity.
  iiia.The gravitational force is assumed to have only low frequency components, therefore a filter with 0.3 Hz cutoff frequency was used.
  iv. From each window, a vector of features was obtained by calculating variables from the time and frequency domain. See 'Codebook.txt' for more details. 

*************************************************
**【Appendix 2: Information of Original dataset】**
*************************************************
Name: Human Activity Recognition Using Smartphones Dataset
Version: 1.0
Source and company information:
Jorge L. Reyes-Ortiz, Davide Anguita, Alessandro Ghio, Luca Oneto.
Smartlab - Non Linear Complex Systems Laboratory
DITEN - Università degli Studi di Genova.
Via Opera Pia 11A, I-16145, Genoa, Italy.
activityrecognition@smartlab.ws
www.smartlab.ws
For each record it is provided:
- Triaxial acceleration from the accelerometer (total acceleration) and the estimated body acceleration.
- Triaxial Angular velocity from the gyroscope. 
- A 561-feature vector with time and frequency domain variables. 
- Its activity label. 
- An identifier of the subject who carried out the experiment.
The dataset includes the following files:
- 'README.txt'
- 'features_info.txt': Shows information about the variables used on the feature vector.
- 'features.txt': List of all features.
- 'activity_labels.txt': Links the class labels with their activity name.
- 'train/X_train.txt': Training set.
- 'train/y_train.txt': Training labels.
- 'test/X_test.txt': Test set.
- 'test/y_test.txt': Test labels.
The following files are available for the train and test data. Their descriptions are equivalent. 
- 'train/subject_train.txt': Each row identifies the subject who performed the activity for each window sample. Its range is from 1 to 30. 
- 'train/Inertial Signals/total_acc_x_train.txt': The acceleration signal from the smartphone accelerometer X axis in standard gravity units 'g'. Every row shows a 128 element vector. The same description applies for the 'total_acc_x_train.txt' and 'total_acc_z_train.txt' files for the Y and Z axis. 
- 'train/Inertial Signals/body_acc_x_train.txt': The body acceleration signal obtained by subtracting the gravity from the total acceleration. 
- 'train/Inertial Signals/body_gyro_x_train.txt': The angular velocity vector measured by the gyroscope for each window sample. The units are radians/second. 
Notes: 
- Features are normalized and bounded within [-1,1].
- Each feature vector is a row on the text file.
For more information about this dataset contact: activityrecognition@smartlab.ws
License:
========
Use of this dataset in publications must be acknowledged by referencing the following publication [1] 
[1] Davide Anguita, Alessandro Ghio, Luca Oneto, Xavier Parra and Jorge L. Reyes-Ortiz. Human Activity Recognition on Smartphones using a Multiclass Hardware-Friendly Support Vector Machine. International Workshop of Ambient Assisted Living (IWAAL 2012). Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain. Dec 2012
This dataset is distributed AS-IS and no responsibility implied or explicit can be addressed to the authors or their institutions for its use or misuse. Any commercial use is prohibited.
Jorge L. Reyes-Ortiz, Alessandro Ghio, Luca Oneto, Davide Anguita. November 2012.
